[
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "The Original Series",
    "Question": "How many times has Captain Kirk's shirt been ripped in this series?",
    "Answer 1": 7,
    "Answer 2": 5,
    "Answer 3": 13,
    "Answer 4": 10,
    "Correct Answer": 13,
    "Narrative": "There were only 79 episodes of this series, so 13 seems a pretty high percentage."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "The Original Series",
    "Question": "In \"City on the Edge of Forever\", what drug was McCoy accidentally \ninjected with?",
    "Answer 1": "Tri-Ox",
    "Answer 2": "Cordrazine",
    "Answer 3": "Hyronalin",
    "Answer 4": "Melanix",
    "Correct Answer": "Cordrazine",
    "Narrative": "McCoy accidentally injected himself due to violent motion of the  ship. As a result, \nhe suffered mental and emotional instability."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "The Original Series",
    "Question": "In the episode \"The Naked Time\", Kevin Riley sang \"I'll Take You Home\n Again Kathleen\". Which of the following famous artists performed\n this song?",
    "Answer 1": "Tony Bennett",
    "Answer 2": "Dean Martin",
    "Answer 3": "Elvis Presley",
    "Answer 4": "Johnny Mathis",
    "Correct Answer": "Elvis Presley",
    "Narrative": "This song was performed by several vocal artists, the most famous of \nwhich include Elvis and Bing Crosby."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "The Original Series",
    "Question": "What organization did Balok represent in the episode \"The Corbomite\nManeuver\"?",
    "Answer 1": "The Romulan Empire",
    "Answer 2": "The First Federation",
    "Answer 3": "The Fesarius",
    "Answer 4": "The T'Kon empire",
    "Correct Answer": "The First Federation",
    "Narrative": "Although the Enterprise's encounter with Balok was significant, The First \nFederation was never seen again in subsequent episodes or movies in the\nfranchise."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "The Original Series",
    "Question": "Which actor who played a regular role in Babylon 5 appeared in several\nepisodes of this series?",
    "Answer 1": "Bruce Boxlietner",
    "Answer 2": "Bill Mumy",
    "Answer 3": "Andreas Katsulas",
    "Answer 4": "Richard Biggs",
    "Correct Answer": "Andreas Katsulas",
    "Narrative": "Katsules portrayed G'Kar in Babylon 5. In the Star Trek franchise, he portrayed\n Commander Tomalak, a Romulan antagonist."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "The Original Series",
    "Question": "Who does Picard say he is in the episode \"Starship Mine\"?",
    "Answer 1": "Mot",
    "Answer 2": "Worf",
    "Answer 3": "Riker",
    "Answer 4": "Geordi",
    "Correct Answer": "Mot",
    "Narrative": "Ironic, since Mot is a barber and Picard is bald."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "Enterprise",
    "Question": "Which actor who played multiple roles across multiple series played\nan Andorian in this series?",
    "Answer 1": "Vaughn Armstrong",
    "Answer 2": "Mark Lenard",
    "Answer 3": "Jeffrey Combs",
    "Answer 4": "J.G. Hertzler",
    "Correct Answer": "Jeffrey Combs",
    "Narrative": "In this series, Combs play the Andorian Shran. Although he was initially an\nantagonist to Captain Archer, they eventually became friends through mutual\nrespect."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Question": "Which Romulan was assassinated in this series as a result of a plot\nto bring the Romulans into the Dominion war?",
    "Answer 1": "Senator Vreenak",
    "Answer 2": "Senator Cretak",
    "Answer 3": "Commander Tomalak",
    "Answer 4": "Sub-Commander N'Vek",
    "Correct Answer": "Senator Vreenak",
    "Narrative": "Captain Sisko conspires with Garak to assasinate a Romulan senator. This is\na very dark plot, considering the ethics the Federation typically adheres to."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "Voyager",
    "Question": "In the episode \"The Omega Directive\", how are Captain Janeway and\n Seven of Nine finally able to contain the Omega particles?",
    "Answer 1": "Level 5 force field",
    "Answer 2": "Harmonic resonance chamber",
    "Answer 3": "They were not able to contain them.",
    "Answer 4": "Multi phasic chamber",
    "Correct Answer": "Harmonic resonance chamber",
    "Narrative": "Seven was able to use knowledge acquired while a Borg drone to temporarily\nstabilize the Omega particles, but only for a very short period of time."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "Enterprise",
    "Question": "Prior to playing Captain Archer, what 1970's TV series did Scott\nBakula star in?",
    "Answer 1": "Sliders",
    "Answer 2": "Quantum Leap",
    "Answer 3": "The Twilight Zone",
    "Answer 4": "The Outer Limits",
    "Correct Answer": "Quantum Leap",
    "Narrative": "Quantum Leap aired on television from March 26, 1989, to May 5, 1993. It ran for a total of five seasons with a total of 97 episodes. It starred\n Scott Bakula as Dr. Sam Beckett."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "The Next Generation",
    "Question": "How old was Geordi La Forge when he received his VISOR?",
    "Answer 1": 15,
    "Answer 2": 20,
    "Answer 3": 5,
    "Answer 4": 10,
    "Correct Answer": 5,
    "Narrative": "Geordi received his VISOR (Visual Instrument and Sensory Organ Replacement)\nwhen he was 5 years old."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "Voyager",
    "Question": "While in the Delta quadrant, Voyager was temporarily fitted with a\nQuantum Slipstream propulsion device. How far was Voyager able\nto travel before this device was removed?",
    "Answer 1": "100 light years",
    "Answer 2": "200 light years",
    "Answer 3": "300 light years",
    "Answer 4": "400 light years",
    "Correct Answer": "300 light years",
    "Narrative": "After traveling 300 light years with the new technology, it was removed due to \nsignificant risk of damage or even destruction of the ship due to its unstable\nproperties."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "The Original Series",
    "Question": "In the episode \"A Piece of the Action\", what was the title of the book\nthat the inhabitants of the planet used as a pattern for their society?",
    "Answer 1": "Mobsters of the 1920's",
    "Answer 2": "Chicago Mobs of the 20's",
    "Answer 3": "Mobsters of New York",
    "Answer 4": "Mobsters of Chicago",
    "Correct Answer": "Chicago Mobs of the 20's",
    "Narrative": "The book was left behind by another Federation ship on an earlier visit to the planet.\nAs a result, the inhabitants of the planet patterned their entire society on book."
  },
  {
    "Category": "Production",
    "Description": "Writing",
    "Question": "D.C. Fontana was a writer for many of the stories in The Original Series.\nWhat do the initials \"D.C.\" stand for?",
    "Answer 1": "David Craig",
    "Answer 2": "Dorothy Catherine",
    "Answer 3": "Donald Conrad",
    "Answer 4": "Diane Colleen",
    "Correct Answer": "Dorothy Catherine",
    "Narrative": "Dorothy Catherine Fontana wrote as D.C. Fontana because in the 1960's and 1970's, when this series was televised, \ngender bias was still an issue."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "The Next Generation",
    "Question": "In the episode \"Masks\", Brent Spiner played how many roles?",
    "Answer 1": 3,
    "Answer 2": 4,
    "Answer 3": 5,
    "Answer 4": 6,
    "Correct Answer": 5,
    "Narrative": "In this episode, Spiner, who still portrayed his regular character, Data, also portrayed 4 personalities of entities from\nthe ship the Enterprise-D was visiting."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "Voyager",
    "Question": "Many well known actors have played guest roles in the franchise. In the\nepisode \"Tsunkatse\", what now famous actor portrayed one of\nSeven of Nine's opponents?",
    "Answer 1": "Dwayne \"The Rock\" Johnson",
    "Answer 2": "Sylvester Stallone",
    "Answer 3": "Mike Tyson",
    "Answer 4": "Sugar Ray Leonard",
    "Correct Answer": "Dwayne \"The Rock\" Johnson",
    "Narrative": "This was one of Dwayne Johnson's early roles, in which he fought 7 of 9 in an arena operated by\nPenk, who had her kidnapped and brought to his arena where he profited from the fights"
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "The Next Generation",
    "Question": "In the episode \"Arsenal of Freedom\", all of the inhabitants of the \nplanet visited by the Enterprise-D's crew were killed. What killed them?",
    "Answer 1": "An attack by the Romulans",
    "Answer 2": "An attack by the Klingons",
    "Answer 3": "Their own weapons",
    "Answer 4": "A deadly virus",
    "Correct Answer": "Their own weapons",
    "Narrative": "The inhabitants of the planet created weapons for sale to other species. As a result of their innovation, their own weapons\nended up killing everyone on the planet."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "Enterprise",
    "Question": "The NX-01 Enterprise did not have shields for protection. What did the\nship have instead?",
    "Answer 1": "Ablative armor",
    "Answer 2": "A polarized hull",
    "Answer 3": "Nothing",
    "Answer 4": "Regenerative armor",
    "Correct Answer": "A polarized hull",
    "Narrative": "Shield technology had not yet been developed at the time Enterprise NX-01 was constructed. Instead, they used a polarized hull, \nwhile created an electro-magnetic field that \"hardened\" the hull."
  },
  {
    "Category": "Motion Pictures",
    "Description": "Nemesis",
    "Question": "In this film, Shinzon killed the entire Romulan senate using what\ntechnology?",
    "Answer 1": "Thalaron radiation",
    "Answer 2": "A photon torpedo",
    "Answer 3": "A deadly virus",
    "Answer 4": "a quantum torpedo",
    "Correct Answer": "Thalaron radiation",
    "Narrative": "Early on in the film, Shinzon, a clone of Jean-Luc Picard, killed the members of the Romulan senate to remove barriers\nto his claim for power."
  },
  {
    "Category": "Motion Pictures",
    "Description": "The Motion Picture",
    "Question": "What was the only prop in this film that was not created specifically\nfor the film?",
    "Answer 1": "Spock's ears",
    "Answer 2": "Phasers",
    "Answer 3": "Tricorders",
    "Answer 4": "Communication earpieces",
    "Correct Answer": "Communication earpieces",
    "Narrative": "Uhura's earpieces were supposed to be created specifically for this film, but they were forgotten. Fortunately, the\nprops from the original television series were found and used instead."
  },
  {
    "Category": "Motion Pictures",
    "Description": "The Motion Picture",
    "Question": "Who invented the original Klingon language",
    "Answer 1": "James Doohan",
    "Answer 2": "Michael Okuna",
    "Answer 3": "Gene Roddenberry",
    "Answer 4": "Andre Bormanis",
    "Correct Answer": "James Doohan",
    "Narrative": "The Klingons first spoke in their native language in this film. Although James Doohan created the basic language for the\nfilm, the later, full language, was written by Michael Okuna."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "The Next Generation",
    "Question": "What character did Captain Picard portray in his holodeck creation as\na private detective?",
    "Answer 1": "Dixon Hill",
    "Answer 2": "Carlos Davis",
    "Answer 3": "Adam West",
    "Answer 4": "Marcus Milton",
    "Correct Answer": "Dixon Hill",
    "Narrative": "Picard portrayed Dixon Hill, a tough guy private detective, in which he often included Data."
  },
  {
    "Category": "Production",
    "Description": "Writing",
    "Question": "Which main Star Trek actor directed the most Star Trek episodes?",
    "Answer 1": "Patrick Stewart",
    "Answer 2": "Jonathan Frakes",
    "Answer 3": "Brent Spiner",
    "Answer 4": "Levar Burton",
    "Correct Answer": "Jonathan Frakes",
    "Narrative": "Although many actors in the Star Trek franchise have taken a turn behind the camera, Frakes directed the most episodes."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "Voyager",
    "Question": "What was the name of Captain Janeway's dog that she left\nbehind in the Alpha quadrant?",
    "Answer 1": "Lady",
    "Answer 2": "Molly",
    "Answer 3": "Precious",
    "Answer 4": "Peanut",
    "Correct Answer": "Molly",
    "Narrative": "Although Captain Janeway fully expected to return to Earth and the company of her dog, she ended up stuck in the\nDelta quadrant. Don't worry. Molly was well cared for in Janeway's absense."
  },
  {
    "Category": "TV Series",
    "Description": "The Next Generation",
    "Question": "In the episode \"The Mind's Eye\", who kidnapped Geordi La Forge to\nuse his VISOR to kill a Klingon ambassador?",
    "Answer 1": "The Romulans",
    "Answer 2": "The Cardassians",
    "Answer 3": "The Changelings",
    "Answer 4": "The Xindi",
    "Correct Answer": "The Romulans",
    "Narrative": "Fortunately, the Romulan's trechory was discovered, and their attempt to kill the Klingon ambassador failed."
  }
]